LAURA FOY UX/UI DESIGNER

@laurafoy_ixd

laurabfoy@gmail.com





ABOUT ME:

I'm a creative IXD Graduate with a love for designing accessible and intuitive interfaces in bold, exciting and imaginative ways. I enjoy solving problems with style and flair, aiming to go above and beyond to create user experiences that not only serve users' needs but also spark joy.

SKILLS:

UI Design, UX Design, Branding, Iconography, Illustration, Graphic Design, Research, Ideation, Iteration, Wireframing, Prototyping, Usability Testing, Documentation & Copywriting, Public Speaking, LMS Administration & Configuration.

TOOLS:

Figma, Illustrator, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Indesign, Miro, Notion, JIRA, Asana, Confluence, HTML5, CSS, Docker, Webflow, Github, Visual Studio Code, Totara TXP, Moodle, Maze, Invision, G-Suite, Microsoft 365, Refined.

EDUCATION:

Belfast School of Art (Ulster University)

BDes Interaction Design (Grade: 1st)

September 2020 - June 2024

Modules Studied Include: Interaction Design Fundamentals, Introduction to Communication Design, Exploring Identity, Imaging and Data Visualisation, Designing with Content, Creative Entrepreneurship, Designing User Experiences, Narrative and Storytelling, Major Project Prototyping, Research and Writing, Major Project, Design Presentation and Reporting.

Loreto Secondary School Letterkenny, Co. Donegal

September 2014 - June 2020

Leaving Certificate: English H2, Irish H4, Maths 02, French H3, Art H1, Biology H2, Music H2.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE:

Synergy Learning, Belfast NI

Intern UX Designer

August 2022 - July 2023

- Developed a proficiency with Figma and contributed to the SL Design System.
- Became a certified administrator for Totara TXP and Moodle.
- Created bespoke concept designs and initiated work on an asset library.
- Designed custom iconography and customised CSS for internal processes.
- Performed UAT/Live site configurations and visual reviews.
- Wrote documentation for various processes.
- Significantly increased UX knowledge and improved time management skills
- Enhanced communication, teamwork, adaptability, and problem-solving skills.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Grove Furnishings, Letterkenny, Co. Donegal

Transition Year Placement

Jan 2018 - May 2018

- Assisted in ensuring cleanliness of the store by dusting furniture, hoovering floors, cleaning windows and glass panels etc.
- Assisted with taking stock inventory.
- Developed communication and hospitality skills by assisting customers.
- Gained an understanding of interior design and composition by helping set up furniture displays.

Donegal Music Education Partnership, Letterkenny, Co. Donegal

Transition Year Placement

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

- First introduction to a collaborative office working environment.
- Developed organisational skills through filing and record keeping.
- · Worked in Excel spreadsheets.
- Assisted in organising the instrument storage room.
- Assisted with other general administrative duties.

OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS:

Currently studying Grade 8 in Saxophone.

Royal Irish Academy of Music

Violin Grade 8

June 2022, Royal Irish Academy of Music

Second Violinist, Donegal Youth Orchestra

Oct 2017 - May 2020

Member of An Grianán Youth Theatre

Sep 2015 - May 2020

Speech and Drama Grade 10, First Class Honours

May 2019, Leinster Academy of Speech and Drama

Senior Certificate of Public Speaking

Nov 2019, Irish Board of Speech and Drama

European Computer Driving License (ECDL)

REFERENCES:

Paul McCormack

Interaction Design Course Tutor Ulster University

p.mccormack@ulster.ac.uk

+44 28 9536 7342

Eimear Corrigan

UX Developer & Placement Mentor/Manager Synergy Learning

eimear.corrigan@synergy-learning.com

+44 28 9042 2000

Martin McGinley

Music Deleopment Manager
Donegal Music Education Partnership

martinmcginley@donegaletb.ie

+353 74 917 6293